{"tossups": [{}, {"question": "This work\u2019s author frequently reminds himself to \u201cErase impressions!\u201d, and to \u201cDo nothing at random.\u201d In order to enforce discipline, this work was written in Koine Greek by its author while fighting against the Quadi on the Hron River. Reminders of mortality are frequent in this work, which synthesizes its author\u2019s Stoic reflections until his death in 180 AD. For the point, name this collection of 12 books of moral philosophy, written by Emperor Marcus Aurelius.", "answer": "<b> Meditations</b> of Marcus Aurelius", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {"question": "This group backed the bishop of Warmia against Casimir IV in the War of the Priests and successfully put down the St. George\u2019s Night Uprising. This group signed the Treaty of Melno after it lost the Gollub War. Alexander Nevsky defeated the forces of this group over Lake Peipus at the Battle of the Ice. Ulrich von Jungingen was killed leading this group to defeat against Polish-Lithuanian forces at the Battle of Grunwald. For the point, name this order of crusading knights of German origin who formed to assist Christian travelers to the holy land.", "answer": "<b> Teutonic Knights</b> or<b> Teutonic Order</b> (accept<b> Order of Brothers of the German House of Saint Mary in Jerusalem</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "These people allied with British colonists in the Covenant Chain. A member of this group, Handsome Lake, founded a religious movement named after their traditional multi-family houses. These people follow the Great Law of Peace, and some practice the Longhouse Religion. In 1722, the Tuscaroras joined them from North Carolina, before which they were known as the \u201cFive Nations\u201d. For the point, the Senecas and Mohawks are members of what confederacy of Native American tribes in upstate New York?", "answer": "<b> Iroquois</b> Confederacy (or League; accept<b> Haudenosaunee</b>; prompt on \u201cFive Nations\u201d or\u201cSix Nations\u201d)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Robert Wilcox launched multiple rebellions in this location. The Blount and Morgan Reports gave contradictory accounts of an uprising here led by U.S. Marines and ordered by John L. Stevens. Lorrin Thurston led the pro-annexation Committee of Safety in this territory. Sanford Dole appointed himself President after the overthrowing of Queen Liliuokalani [\u201dlily\u201d-oh-kalani] in, for the point, what Pacific territory that became the 50th U.S. state?", "answer": "<b> Hawaii</b> (accept any description of the kingdom, territory, or state of<b> Hawaii</b>) Page 1", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "German businessman John Rabe established a \u201cSafety Zone\u201d before a battle in this city. En route to a battle in this city, two soldiers had a contest to see who could be the first to kill 100 people using their swords. A treaty that was signed in this city ceded Hong Kong to Britain and ended the first Opium War. Hundreds of thousands of people were killed during the Second Sino-Japanese War in the \u201cRape\u201d of, for the point, what Chinese city?", "answer": "<b> Nanking</b> or<b> Nanjing</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "The founder of this religion was imprisoned in the Siyah-Chal, and declared in the Ridvan gardens that he was \u201cHe whom God shall make manifest.\u201d William Sears, the last living Hand of the Cause of this religion, died in 1992. The history of this religion is the subject of<em> God Passes By</em> by Shoghi Effendi. This religion is governed by the Universal House of Justice in Haifa, Israel, and was founded by followers of the Bab. For the point, name this Iranian religion founded by Baha\u2019u\u2019llah.", "answer": "<b> Baha\u2019i</b> Faith", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {"question": "A G minor piece written for this occasion ends with a pastorale and was the eighth concerto grosso of Arcangelo Corelli\u2019s Opus 6. Songs for this occasion include ones named for Wexford and Coventry, whose performance was banned by the Rump Parliament of Oliver Cromwell. King George II began a tradition of standing up during another piece performed around this holiday. For the point, Handel\u2019s<em> Messiah</em> and carols such as \u201cO Holy Night\u201d are performed for what December holiday?", "answer": "<b> Christmas</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This group of people asked if they would be \u201cthe only ones for whom the iron age will forever exist\u201din a petition that also included 10 proposed decrees presented to the National Assembly. In October 1789, in response to the skyrocketing price of bread, these people marched to Versailles and brought Louis XVI and his family back to Paris. For the point, name this demographic, the subject of an Olympe de Gouge treatise that demanded gender equality.", "answer": "<b> women</b> (or equivalents; prompt on \u201cthe French\u201d or \u201cthe Third Estate\u201d)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "One agreement concerning oil production in this body of water was signed by Heydra Aliyev in 1994 and was known as the \u201cContract of the Century.\u201d The Garabogazkol lagoon lies to the east of this body of water, where sturgeon overfishing is a major concern. A pipeline running from this sea goes through Tbilisi to Ceyhan on the Mediterranean, delivering oil from Baku. The Volga River flows into, for the point, what largest saltwater lake in the world, a sea that borders countries like Azerbaijan and Russia?", "answer": "<b> Caspian</b> Sea", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "This man noted \u201cThe system broken, the schools closed, the prisons open\u201d in a song that sampled King Crimson, and remixed a track that sampled Shirley Bassey to add a verse about blood diamonds. This rapper of \u201cPOWER\u201d and \u201cDiamonds from Sierra Leone\u201d caused controversy at a benefit concert for Hurricane Katrina when he stated that \u201cGeorge Bush doesn\u2019t care about black people.\u201d for the point, name this rapper who interrupted Taylor Swift at the VMAs and recorded \u201cGold Digger.\u201d", "answer": "<b> Kanye West</b> (accept either; prompt on \u201cYe\u201d or \u201cYeezy\u201d)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "The Allon Plan was a proposal to partition territory involved in this conflict. The<em> USS Liberty</em> was sunk during this conflict, whose end led to the adoption of UN Security Council Resolution 242. Shortly before this conflict, the Straits of Tiran were closed by Gamal Abdel Nasser. The winning side in this conflict gained the Sinai Peninsula, the West Bank and the Golan Heights thanks to a surprise attack that devastated the Egyptian air force. For the point, name this 1967 Arab-Israeli war that lasted less than a week.", "answer": "<b> Six Day</b> War (accept<b> Third Arab-Israeli</b> War; prompt on Arab-Israeli War before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "The forces of one ruler with this name put down the Monmouth Rebellion, which led to trials known as the Bloody Assizes. One ruler with this name died at the Battle of Flodden Field. The birth of Mary of Modena\u2019s son with this name helped spark the Glorious Revolution. One ruler with this name was targeted by Robert Catesby and Guy Fawkes in the Gunpowder Plot. For the point, give this name of seven Kings of Scotland and the first Stuart King of England.", "answer": "<b> James</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This man consolidated the power of the federal government with the Seven Laws. This man forced Isidro Barradas to sign the Capitulation of Pueblo Viejo. This target of the Plan of Ayutla was wounded by French grapeshot during the Pastry War. This man signed the Treaty of Velasco with the Republic of Texas after the Battle of San Jacinto. For the point, name this wooden-legged Mexican general who won the Battle of the Alamo.", "answer": "Antonio Lopez de<b> Santa Anna</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This nation lost a match whose nickname refers to an injury to Ervin Zador. After controversially losing to this nation, Doug Collins and his teammates refused to accept silver medals. This nation, which lost the 1956 \u201cBlood in the Water\u201d water polo match to Hungary, lost a semi-final game at Lake Placid in the \u201cMiracle on Ice\u201d. For the point, name this nation that boycotted the 1984 Los Angeles Summer Olympics after hosting the previous Summer Olympics in Moscow.", "answer": "<b> Soviet Union</b> (or<b> U</b>nion of<b> S</b>oviet<b> S</b>ocialist<b> R</b>epublics; do not accept or prompt on Russia)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "\u201d", "answer": "William Butler<b> Yeats</b>", "metadata": "Literature - British Literature - Poetry"}, {"question": "The city was the subject of the Pabst Plan. A mass suicide occurred on 18 Ulica Mila in this city, where a failed uprising was detailed in the Stroop Report. The Home Army launched a 1944 uprising in this city, which was defeated and led to the planned destruction of 90% of this city\u2019s buildings. Mordechai Anielewicz [ahn-yail-eh-vitch] led an uprising against the Nazis in this city\u2019s Jewish Quarter, the largest Jewish ghetto in World War II Europe. For the point, name this capital of Poland.", "answer": "<b> Warsaw</b> [or<b> Warsawa</b>]", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "For the point, name this upper house of the U.S. Congress, currently consisting of 100 members.", "answer": "United States<b> Senate</b> (do not accept \u201cCongress\u201d) Page 4", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "During the 1980\u2019s, this country\u2019s army attacked civilians in Matabeleland in the Gukurahundi. Its president at the time, Canaan Banana, was convicted for homosexuality in 1998. The Movement for Democratic Change, an opposition party in this country, is led by a former union leader who left the Patriotic Front of the ruling ZANU party, Morgan Tsvangirai [CHAN-girr-eye]. For the point, name this African country that has suffered from hyperinflation under Robert Mugabe.", "answer": "<b> Zimbabwe</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "A large, monochromatic white depiction of this object was made using encaustic, and was inspired by a 1954 dream. The artist of that painting also depicted three of these objects in different sizes on top of each other. A photograph by Joe Rosenthal depicts five servicemen lifting one of these items atop Mount Suribachi on Iwo Jima. Jasper Johns frequently painted, for the point, what red, white, and blue banner that was supposedly first sewn by Betsy Ross?", "answer": "<b> American flag</b>s (prompt on \u201cflags\u201d)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "Sixty German soldiers were killed on New Year\u2019s Day in the Chenogne massacre during this battle. During this battle, Omar Bradley was detained when one of his men believed that the capital of Illinois was Chicago. During this battle, the Meuse River offensive stalled, and Anthony McAuliffe refused to surrender despite being surrounded at Bastogne within enemy lines. For the point, name this last major German offensive on the Western Front in World War II, named for the deformation caused in the American line.", "answer": "Battle of the<b> Bulge</b> (accept<b> Ardennes</b> Offensive or equivalents)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "A structure along this river was deliberately destroyed near Caernarvon to protect a larger population center, on the orders of banker James Butler. This river\u2019s Mounds Landing was the site of a deadly breach where African-Americans were forced to pile sandbags at gunpoint. Relief efforts along this river were led by the \u201cGreat Humanitarian,\u201d Secretary of Commerce Herbert Hoover, in contrast to President Coolidge\u2019s inaction. For the point, a \u201cGreat\u201d 1927 flood affected what river, whose banks are home to the cities of St. Louis and New Orleans?", "answer": "<b> Mississippi</b> River <b>Extra Question</b> Only read if moderator botches a question.", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Three Flags Day commemorates the finalization of this agreement, and Fort Osage was built in the wake of this agreement. Francois de Barbe-Marbois officially presented this agreement to Robert Livingston, the American negotiator of this agreement, and the Haitian Revolution reinforced this agreement\u2019s necessity to Napoleon. Lewis and Clark were sent to explore the land acquired through this agreement. For the point, name this land sale that dramatically expanded the size of the United States under Thomas Jefferson\u2019s presidency.", "answer": "<b> Louisiana Purchase</b> Page 6", "metadata": "History - American History"}], "bonuses": []}